IAN FLESHMAN-COOPER

Kirkland, WA 98033

Phone: (425) 495-3453 | Email: ian.fleshmancooper@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-fleshman-cooper-934995163/

GitHub: https://github.com/Ianaac27

Portfolio: https://ianaac27.github.io/Portfolio 2.0/index.html

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a BA and Summa Cum Laude honors in Mathematics and IT from Northwest University. Certificate in Full-Stack web development from the University of Washington. Knowledge in Information Systems and numerical problem solving, as well as acquiring skills in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Currently an Academic Advisor for Northwest University for the past two years, with valuable experience in solving solutions to create efficiency, consultant for students, and working with/training a team of advisors to reach team goals. Developed a system for updating current software to help with system maintenance and data tracking. My aim is to bring these fundamentals to a much more technical scale. With a drive to learn and proven experience as a reliable team player and supportive leader I will serve and help others achieve goals through efficiency and simplicity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL

Applications: jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Web Services API, Node.JS

PROJECTS

Game & GIF

https://github.com/Tskading/Game-Meme | https://tskading.github.io/Game-Meme/

- Game & GIF is a website that contains a database of video game information along with a variety of GIFs that correlate with the game.
- I was responsible for back-end responsibilities such as applying functions and setting API's to make the site more dynamic.
- JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, RAWG API, GIPHY API, Slack, Zoom

Workday Scheduler

https://github.com/lanaac27/Work_Day_Scheduler | https://ianaac27.github.io/Work_Day_Scheduler/

- An application that is meant to keep track of the users' daily agenda within their workday hours.
- Dynamic feature designed to change the color as each hour passes to determine whether the hour is current, past, or in the future.
- JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Moments.JS

Password Generator

https://github.com/lanaac27/Password_Generator | https://ianaac27.github.io/Password_Generator/

- This application will generate a random password based off a series of prompts and confirmations for the user.
- Functionality to generate a password randomly, as well as reset.
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

NPP Academic Advisor Northwest University

2018 – Present Kirkland, WA

Assist students with a plan for their higher education. Consulting with students and staff and managing tasks and computer systems. Familiarity with many software applications such as Excel, Access, Power Campus, Sales Force, Calendly, Microsoft 365, Teams, and Zoom. *Key Accomplishments:*

• Leadership involving training and interviewing new employees. Developed a system for updating current software to help with system maintenance and data tracking.

Technology Assistant Sultan School District

2017 - 2018

Sultan, WA

Repair computers, projectors and mimeo boards - such as keyboards, screens, hard drive replacements, etc.

Para-Educator Sultan School District 2014 - 2018

Sultan, WA

Support children and teens in their learning through encouragement, brainstorming for ideas, social expectations, as well as relationship building. Classroom management, communication with students and their parents, and tutoring and one-on-one support. *Key Accomplishments:*

Had been recognized as employee of the month twice by my colleagues and peers.

EDUCATION

Full- Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Washington – Seattle, WA 24-week intensive program gaining technical programming skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React JS, MongoDB, Node.JS as well as going in depth with Algorithms, Efficiency, and Data Structures.

BA in Mathematics and Information Technology: Northwest University - Kirkland, WA

• 3.91 GPA – Summa Cum Laude – Annual Dean's List

Associates Degree: Shoreline Community College - Shoreline, WA

• 3.67 GPA – Annual Dean's List